Brief Summary

I have 5 years of professional experience that I have gained in an international freight forwarder. I am perceived as an energetic, organised and committed person. Enthusiastic candidate with engineering background. Well versed with Project Management duties, theories and analysis. I am looking for an opportunity in Project Management in which I will use my skills and experience to implement the company quidelines.

Work Experience

10/2018 - 12/2018

Business Development Intern at Ambergau-Immobilien Berlin

- Conducted feasible studies, financial analysis and due diligence for all new property acquisitions.
- Created and designed user-friendly sales materials for prospective and existing customers
- Developed business-network models for the operation of pro formats, acquisition and Customer oriented development.

07/2017 - 09/2018

Business Development Regional Project Manager at Krishna Corporation Ltd. India

- Developed, coordinated and implemented sales strategies that identified and produced new business in two different states.
- Established CRM to increase sales, improve sales forecasting, and enhance account tracking on new and existing clients.
- Maintained and cultivated relationships with 7 companies for new opportunities by proper stakeholder management skills.
- Successfully lowered the turnover rate from 10% to 3% by implementing stronger guidelines for interviewing and screening potential candidates.

12/2015-06/2017

Project Manager at Krishna Corporation Ltd. India

- Expertise in scope development, decision making and project management cycle process according to CSI and PMP principles in 7 successful projects.
- Manage 3 assigned industrial and 1 commercial construction projects, including budget, execution and performance, and subcontracting delivery.
- Repayment of more than \$ 400,000 in incidental costs and damages with detailed documentation and negotiations with the engineering company.
- Executed the on-site quantitative sheets as per the BOM (Bill of materials) and saved 5% of the total project budget.

06/2014-11/2015

Project Engineer at Krishna Corporation Ltd. India

- Responsible for research, mathematical analysis, structure designs, delivery and project life cycle operations as a company representative.
- Developed a unique table-based problem reporting system and created a weekly summary of construction activities.
- Supervised 65-man staff in Deesa construction project and completed with tight deadline schedule.
- Contributed to cost savings by cutting travel expenses and optimizing office supply purchases.

Education

2019-20

Arden University, Berlin

Master's in Project Management (APM Accredited)
Master thesis- Integrated agile methodology

2010-14

Gujarat Technological University, India

Bachelor's in Civil engineering

Languages

Hindi (mother tongue), English (fluent), German (Intermediate)



Prashant Pandey

Address:

Kaiserin-Augusta-Alee 4, 10553 Berlin

Contact Number:

+49-17676490289

Email:

ppandey966@gmail.com

Nationality

Indian

Date Of Birth:

01.11.1992

IT Skills

- Programme: MS Word, MS Excel, MS Power Point
- SPSS IBM
- Auto CAD
- MiniTAB 18 Analytics
- Google analytics
- ERP SAP
- Primavera

Soft Skills

- Leadership
- Negotiation
- Risk management
- Problem-solving
- Communication skills
- Presentation skills

Achievements

- 11/2018- Facilitation of the first international sales success in Ambergau-Immobilien.
- 06/2017-3% increase in revenue generation at Krishna Corporation Ltd.
- 11/2015- Award as "Young project manager" for the timely and successful implementation of 3 projects.

Hobbies

- Learning new programs such as Technomatix plant simulation process, Work through (HR Tools).
- Football (national player of FUTSAL India).